Kedgard Cordero

Software Engineer

Email: geckob4i@gmail.com Phone: 651-231-0126

Location: Lino Lakes, Minnesota

GitHub: https://github.com/Kenny4297

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kedgard-cordero/Portfolio: https://kenny4297.github.io/React-Portfolio/

About Me

2 years of self-study with a certificate from the University of Minnesota Coding Boot Camp. Enjoys working in fast paced environments and learning anything regarding software development. Curious with a love to solve problems, always malleable to company standards.

Skills

Front-End: React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery

Back-end: Python, Node.js, Express.js

Databases: SQL, MongoDB

Additional Tools: Sequelize, MySQL, Mongoose, Jest

Experience

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp, University of Minnesota

Minneapolis, Minnesota

2022-2023

- Lead Programmer for group project 1 and 3, Project Manager for group project 2.
- Average assignment result of 101.58% with consistent feedback regarding clean, polished code.
- Directed weekly tutor sessions for fellow students.
- Improved professor's MERN Authentication stack starter code.

Hazelwood Food and Drink, Tonka Bay - Server Trainer

Tonka Bay, Minnesota

2016-2022

- Lead trainer for over 140 servers at Tonka Bay location in collaboration with corporate management.
- Onboarded over 90 servers while opening 3 different multi-million-dollar restaurants across Minneapolis-St. Paul.
- Refined and revised training materials for multiple departments including Spanish translation services.

Featured Projects

Be Tethical! A full-stack content management system that allows users to post thoughts about any video game, and also comment on others' thoughts.

- Technologies: JavaScript, CSS, bcrypt, Express-Handlebars, Node.js, SQL, MySQL, Sequelize
- Deployed at: https://be-tethical-production.up.railway.app/

Weather App A front end application that tracks the weather and the five-day forecast in any city around the globe.

- Technologies: JavaScript, Bootstrap, Open Weather API
- Deployed at: https://kenny4297.github.io/Weather-App-API/

Education

Minnesota State University, Mankato

Teaching and Learning (MS)

2014-2016

- Documented 800 hours as student teacher
 - Owatonna High School, Minnesota
 - Waseca High School, Minnesota
 - o Liceo Experimental Bilingue, Turrialba, Costa Rica